<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<MagicProperty xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <AttunementFeatures>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Magic Weapon</Name>
      <Text>The Axe of the Dwarvish Lords is a magic weapon that grants a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. The axe also functions as a belt of dwarvenkind, a dwarven thrower, and a sword of sharpness.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
    <AbilityScoreFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Belt of Dwarvenkind</Name>
      <Text>Your Constitution score increases by 2, to a maximum of 20.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>true</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Modifier>AddScore</Modifier>
      <Strength>0</Strength>
      <Constitution>2</Constitution>
      <Dexterity>0</Dexterity>
      <Intelligence>0</Intelligence>
      <Wisdom>0</Wisdom>
      <Charisma>0</Charisma>
    </AbilityScoreFeature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Belt of Dwarvenkind</Name>
      <Text>You have advantage on Charisma (Persuasion) checks made to interact with dwarves.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
    <ResistanceFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Belt of Dwarvenkind</Name>
      <Text>If you aren’t a dwarf, you have advantage on saving throws against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite>Not a dwarf</Prerequisite>
      <Resistances>
        <string>poison</string>
      </Resistances>
      <Vulnerabilities />
      <Immunities />
      <SavingThrowAdvantages>
        <string>poison</string>
      </SavingThrowAdvantages>
    </ResistanceFeature>
    <VisionFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Belt of Dwarvenkind</Name>
      <Text>If you aren’t a dwarf, you have darkvision out to a range of 60 feet.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite>Not a dwarf</Prerequisite>
      <Range>60</Range>
    </VisionFeature>
    <LanguageProficiencyFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Belt of Dwarvenkind</Name>
      <Text>If you aren’t a dwarf, you can speak, read, and write Dwarvish.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>true</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite>Not a dwarf</Prerequisite>
      <Languages>
        <string>Dwarvish</string>
      </Languages>
    </LanguageProficiencyFeature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Dwarven Thrower</Name>
      <Text>This Axe of the Dwarvish Lords has the thrown property with a normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet. When you hit with a ranged attack using this weapon, it deals an extra 1d8 damage or, if the target is a giant, 2d8 damage. Immediately after the attack, the weapon flies back to your hand.
Proficiency with a warhammer allows you to add your proficiency bonus to the attack roll for any attack you make with it.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Other</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Sword of Sharpness</Name>
      <Text>When you attack an object with the Axe of the Dwarvish Lords and hit, maximize your weapon damage dice against the target.
When you attack a creature with the Axe of the Dwarvish Lords and roll a 20 on the attack roll, that target takes an extra 4d6 slashing damage. Then roll another d20. If you roll a 20, you lop off one of the target's limbs, with the effect of such loss determined by the DM. If the creature has no limb to sever, you lop off a portion of its body instead.
In addition, you can speak the sword's command word to cause the blade to shed bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. Speaking the command word again or sheathing the sword puts out the light.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Other</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Random Properties</Name>
      <Text>The axe has the following randomly determined properties:
• 2 minor beneficial properties
• 1 major beneficial property
• 2 minor detrimental properties</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>true</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
    <MultiFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Blessings of Moradin</Name>
      <Text>If you are a dwarf attuned to the axe, you gain the following benefits:
• You have immunity to poison damage.
• The range of your darkvision increases by 60 feet.
• You gain proficiency with artisan's tools related to blacksmithing, brewing, and stonemasonry.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <Features>
        <ToolProficiencyFeature>
          <Keywords />
          <Name />
          <Text />
          <Level>0</Level>
          <Hidden>true</Hidden>
          <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
          <Action>Hidden</Action>
          <Prerequisite />
          <Tools>
            <string>Smith’s tools</string>
            <string>Brewer’s supplies</string>
            <string>Mason’s tools</string>
          </Tools>
        </ToolProficiencyFeature>
        <VisionFeature>
          <Keywords />
          <Name />
          <Text />
          <Level>0</Level>
          <Hidden>true</Hidden>
          <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
          <Action>Hidden</Action>
          <Prerequisite />
          <Range>120</Range>
        </VisionFeature>
        <ResistanceFeature>
          <Keywords />
          <Name />
          <Text />
          <Level>0</Level>
          <Hidden>false</Hidden>
          <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
          <Action>Hidden</Action>
          <Prerequisite />
          <Resistances />
          <Vulnerabilities />
          <Immunities>
            <string>poison</string>
          </Immunities>
          <SavingThrowAdvantages />
        </ResistanceFeature>
      </Features>
      <Condition>Race = 'dwarf'</Condition>
      <Source>Dungeon Master's Guide</Source>
    </MultiFeature>
    <BonusSpellFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Conjure Earth Elemental</Name>
      <Text>If you are holding the axe, you can use your action to cast the conjure elemental spell from it, summoning an earth elemental. You can't use this property again until the next dawn.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Action</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <Spell>Conjure Elemental</Spell>
      <SpellCastingAbility>None</SpellCastingAbility>
      <SpellCastModifier>Dawn</SpellCastModifier>
      <KeywordsToAdd />
    </BonusSpellFeature>
    <BonusSpellFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Travel the Depths</Name>
      <Text>You can use an action to touch the axe to a fixed piece of dwarven stonework and cast the teleport spell from the axe. If your intended destination is underground, there is no chance of a mishap or arriving somewhere unexpected. You can't use this property again until 3 days have passed.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Action</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <Spell>Teleport</Spell>
      <SpellCastingAbility>None</SpellCastingAbility>
      <SpellCastModifier>Special</SpellCastModifier>
      <KeywordsToAdd />
    </BonusSpellFeature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Curse</Name>
      <Text>The axe bears a curse that affects any non-dwarf that becomes attuned to it. Even if the attunement ends, the curse remains. With each passing day, the creature's physical appearance and stature become more dwarflike. After seven days, the creature looks like a typical dwarf, but the creature neither loses its racial traits nor gains the racial traits of a dwarf. The physical changes wrought by the axe aren't considered magical in nature (and therefore can't be dispelled), but they can be undone by any effect that removes a curse, such as a greater restoration or remove curse spell.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
  </AttunementFeatures>
  <CarryFeatures>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Destroying the Axe</Name>
      <Text>The only way to destroy the axe is to melt it down in the Earthheart Forge, where it was created. It must remain in the burning forge for fifty years before it finally succumbs to the fire and is consumed.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>true</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
  </CarryFeatures>
  <EquipFeatures />
  <AttunedEquipFeatures />
  <OnUseFeatures />
  <AttunedOnUseFeatures>
    <BonusFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name />
      <Text />
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>true</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <Condition>Weapon</Condition>
      <Skills />
      <SkillBonus>0</SkillBonus>
      <SkillPassive>false</SkillPassive>
      <AttackBonus>3</AttackBonus>
      <DamageBonus>3</DamageBonus>
      <SaveDCBonus>0</SaveDCBonus>
      <InitiativeBonus>0</InitiativeBonus>
      <DamageBonusModifier>None</DamageBonusModifier>
      <BaseAbility>None</BaseAbility>
      <SavingThrowBonus>0</SavingThrowBonus>
      <ProficiencyBonus>0</ProficiencyBonus>
      <SavingThrowAbility>None</SavingThrowAbility>
      <SizeChange>0</SizeChange>
      <ProficiencyOptions>
        <string>Warhammer</string>
      </ProficiencyOptions>
    </BonusFeature>
  </AttunedOnUseFeatures>
  <Requirement>Weapon (battleaxe)</Requirement>
  <Name>Axe of the Dwarvish Lords</Name>
  <Description>Seeing the peril his people faced, a young dwarf prince came to believe that his people needed something to unite them. Thus, he set out to forge a weapon that would be such a symbol.
Venturing deep under the mountains, deeper than any dwarf had ever delved, the young prince came to the blazing heart of a great volcano. With the aid of Moradin, the dwarven god of creation, he first crafted four great tools: the Brutal Pick, the Earthheart Forge, the Anvil of Songs, and the Shaping Hammer. With them, he forged the Axe of the Dwarvish Lords.
Armed with the artifact, the prince returned to the dwarf clans and brought peace. His axe ended grudges and answered slights. The clans became allies, and they threw back their enemies and enjoyed an era of prosperity. This young dwarf is remembered as the First King. When he became old, he passed the weapon, which had become his badge of office, to his heir. The rightful inheritors passed the axe on for many generations.
Later, in a dark era marked by treachery and wickedness, the axe was lost in a bloody civil war fomented by greed for its power and the status it bestowed. Centuries later, the dwarves still search for the axe, and many adventurers have made careers of chasing after rumors and plundering old vaults to find it.</Description>
  <Slot>Weapon</Slot>
  <Base>Weapon and Battleaxe</Base>
  <Source>Dungeon Master's Guide</Source>
  <PostName>of the Dwarvish Lords</PostName>
  <Rarity>Artifact</Rarity>
</MagicProperty>