<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SubRace xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Features>
    <AbilityScoreFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Ability Score Increase</Name>
      <Text>Your Constitution score increases by 1.</Text>
      <Level>1</Level>
      <Hidden>true</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Modifier>AddScore</Modifier>
      <Strength>0</Strength>
      <Constitution>1</Constitution>
      <Dexterity>0</Dexterity>
      <Intelligence>0</Intelligence>
      <Wisdom>0</Wisdom>
      <Charisma>0</Charisma>
    </AbilityScoreFeature>
    <ResistanceFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Stout Resilience</Name>
      <Text>You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage.</Text>
      <Level>1</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <Resistances />
      <Vulnerabilities>
        <string>poison</string>
      </Vulnerabilities>
      <Immunities />
      <SavingThrowAdvantages>
        <string>poison</string>
      </SavingThrowAdvantages>
    </ResistanceFeature>
  </Features>
  <Descriptions />
  <Source>Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide</Source>
  <Name>Strongheart</Name>
  <Description>Creatures of the earth who love a warm hearth and pleasant company, strongheart halflings are folks of few enemies and many friends. Stronghearts are sometimes referred to fondly by members of other races as "the good folk," for little upsets stronghearts or corrupts their spirit. To many of them, the greatest fear is to live in a world of poor company and mean intent, where one lacks freedom and the comfort of friendship.
When strongheart halflings settle into a place, they intend to stay. It's not unusual for a dynasty of stronghearts to live in the same place for a few centuries. Strongheart halflings don't develop these homes in seclusion. On the contrary, they do their best to fit into the local community and become an essential part of it. Their viewpoint stresses cooperation above all other traits, and the ability to work well with others is the most valued behavior in their lands.
Pushed from their nests, strongheart haflings typically try to have as many comforts of home with them as possible. Non-stronghearts with a more practical bent can find strongheart travel habits maddening, but their lightfoot cousins typically enjoy the novelty of it—so long as the lightfoots don't have to carry any of the baggage.
While often stereotyped as fat and lazy due to their homebound mindset and obsession with fine food, strongheart halfings are typically quite industrious. Nimble hands, their patient mindset, and their emphasis on quality makes them excellent weavers, potters, wood carvers, basket makers, painters, and farmers. 
Strongheart halflings have all the racial traits of stouts in the Player's Handbook. Strongheart halflings are shorter on average than their lightfoot kin, and tend to have rounder faces. They have the skin tones and hair colors of humans, with most having brown hair. Unlike their lightfoot cousins, strongheart halflings often have blond or black hair and blue or green eyes. Males don't grow beards or mustaches, but both males and females can grow sideburns down to mid-cheek, and both genders plait them into long braids.</Description>
  <ParentRace>Halfling</ParentRace>
</SubRace>