<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<FeatureContainer xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Features>
    <MultiFeature>
      <Keywords>
        <Keyword>
          <Name>mystic</Name>
        </Keyword>
        <Keyword>
          <Name>discipline</Name>
        </Keyword>
        <Keyword>
          <Name>avatar</Name>
        </Keyword>
      </Keywords>
      <Name>Crown of Despair</Name>
      <Text>You have learned to harvest seeds of despair in a creature’s psyche, wracking it with self-doubt and inaction.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>true</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite>Avatar Discipline</Prerequisite>
      <Features>
        <Feature>
          <Keywords />
          <Name>Crown of Despair - Psychic Focus</Name>
          <Text>While focused on this discipline, you have advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks. </Text>
          <Level>0</Level>
          <Hidden>false</Hidden>
          <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
          <Action>Bonus</Action>
          <Prerequisite />
        </Feature>
        <Feature>
          <Keywords />
          <Name>Crown of Despair - Crowned in Sorrow (1–7 psi)</Name>
          <Text>As an action, one creature you can see within 60 feet of you must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, it takes 1d8 psychic damage per psi point spent, and it can’t take reactions until the start of its next turn. On a successful save, it takes half as much damage. </Text>
          <Level>0</Level>
          <Hidden>false</Hidden>
          <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
          <Action>Action</Action>
          <Prerequisite />
        </Feature>
        <Feature>
          <Keywords />
          <Name>Crown of Despair - Call to Inaction (2 psi; conc., 10 min.)</Name>
          <Text>If you spend 1 minute conversing with a creature, you can attempt to seed it with overwhelming ennui. At the end of the minute, you can use an action to force the creature to make a Wisdom saving throw. The save automatically succeeds if the target is immune to being charmed. On a failed save, it sits and is incapacitated until your concentration ends. This effect immediately ends if the target or any ally it can see is attacked or takes damage. On a successful save, the creature is unaffected and has no inkling of your attempt to bend its will.</Text>
          <Level>0</Level>
          <Hidden>false</Hidden>
          <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
          <Action>Other</Action>
          <Prerequisite />
        </Feature>
        <Feature>
          <Keywords />
          <Name>Crown of Despair - Visions of Despair (3 psi)</Name>
          <Text>As an action, you force one creature you can see within 60 feet of you to make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, it takes 3d6 psychic damage, and its speed is reduced to 0 until the end of its next turn. On a successful save, it takes half as much damage. You can increase the damage by 1d6 per additional psi point spent on it.</Text>
          <Level>0</Level>
          <Hidden>false</Hidden>
          <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
          <Action>Action</Action>
          <Prerequisite />
        </Feature>
        <Feature>
          <Keywords />
          <Name>Crown of Despair - Dolorous Mind (5 psi; conc., 1 min.)</Name>
          <Text>As an action, you choose one creature you can see within 60 feet of you. It must succeed on a Charisma saving throw, or it is incapacitated and has a speed of 0 until your concentration ends. It can repeat this saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</Text>
          <Level>0</Level>
          <Hidden>false</Hidden>
          <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
          <Action>Action</Action>
          <Prerequisite />
        </Feature>
      </Features>
      <Source>Unearthed Arcana The Mystic Class</Source>
    </MultiFeature>
  </Features>
  <Source>Unearthed Arcana The Mystic Class</Source>
</FeatureContainer>