<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<FeatureContainer xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Features>
    <MultiFeature>
      <Keywords>
        <Keyword>
          <Name>mystic</Name>
        </Keyword>
        <Keyword>
          <Name>discipline</Name>
        </Keyword>
        <Keyword>
          <Name>wujen</Name>
        </Keyword>
      </Keywords>
      <Name>Mastery of Fire</Name>
      <Text>You align your mind with the energy of elemental fire.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>true</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite>Wu Jen Discipline</Prerequisite>
      <Features>
        <Feature>
          <Keywords />
          <Name>Mastery of Fire - Psychic Focus</Name>
          <Text>While focused on this discipline, you gain resistance to fire damage, and you gain a +2 bonus to rolls for fire damage.</Text>
          <Level>0</Level>
          <Hidden>false</Hidden>
          <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
          <Action>Bonus</Action>
          <Prerequisite />
        </Feature>
        <Feature>
          <Keywords />
          <Name>Mastery of Fire - Combustion (1–7 psi; conc., 1 min.)</Name>
          <Text>As an action, choose one creature or object you can see within 120 feet of you. The target must make a Constitution save. On a failed save, the target takes 1d10 fire damage per psi point spent, and it catches on fire, taking 1d6 fire damage at the end of each of its turns until your concentration ends or until it or a creature adjacent to it extinguishes the flames with an action. On a successful save, the target takes half as much damage and doesn’t catch on fire.</Text>
          <Level>0</Level>
          <Hidden>false</Hidden>
          <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
          <Action>Action</Action>
          <Prerequisite />
        </Feature>
        <Feature>
          <Keywords />
          <Name>Mastery of Fire - Rolling Flame (3 psi; conc., 1 min.)</Name>
          <Text>As an action, you create fire in a 20-foot-by-20-foot cube within 5 feet of you. The fire lasts until your concentration ends. Any creature in that area when you use this ability and any creature that ends its turn there takes 5 fire damage.</Text>
          <Level>0</Level>
          <Hidden>false</Hidden>
          <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
          <Action>Action</Action>
          <Prerequisite />
        </Feature>
        <Feature>
          <Keywords />
          <Name>Mastery of Fire - Detonation (5 psi)</Name>
          <Text>As an action, you create a fiery explosion at a point you can see within 120 feet of you. Each creature in a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on that point must make a Constitution saving throw, taking 7d6 fire damage and being knocked prone on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</Text>
          <Level>0</Level>
          <Hidden>false</Hidden>
          <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
          <Action>Action</Action>
          <Prerequisite />
        </Feature>
        <Feature>
          <Keywords />
          <Name>Mastery of Fire - Fire Form (5 psi; conc., 1 min.)</Name>
          <Text>As a bonus action, you become wreathed in flames until your concentration ends. Any creature that end its turn within 5 feet of you takes 3d6 fire damage.</Text>
          <Level>0</Level>
          <Hidden>false</Hidden>
          <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
          <Action>Bonus</Action>
          <Prerequisite />
        </Feature>
        <FormsCompanionsFeature>
          <Keywords />
          <Name>Mastery of Fire - Animate Fire (7 psi; conc., 1 hr.)</Name>
          <Text>As an action, you cause a fire elemental to appear in an unoccupied space you can see within 120 feet of you. The elemental lasts until your concentration ends, and it obeys your verbal commands. In combat, roll for its initiative, and choose its behavior during its turns. When this effect ends, the elemental disappears. See the Monster Manual for its stat block.</Text>
          <Level>0</Level>
          <Hidden>false</Hidden>
          <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
          <Action>Hidden</Action>
          <Prerequisite />
          <DisplayName>Wu Jen Summons</DisplayName>
          <UniqueID>MYSTIC_WU_JEN_SUMMONS</UniqueID>
          <FormsCompanionsOptions>Name = "Fire Elemental"</FormsCompanionsOptions>
          <FormsCompanionsCount>-1</FormsCompanionsCount>
        </FormsCompanionsFeature>
      </Features>
      <Source>Unearthed Arcana The Mystic Class</Source>
    </MultiFeature>
  </Features>
  <Source>Unearthed Arcana The Mystic Class</Source>
</FeatureContainer>