<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<MagicProperty xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <AttunementFeatures>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Wind Step</Name>
      <Text>As an action, you ﬂy up to 20 feet. If you don't land at the end of this flight, you fall unless you have another means of staying aloft.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Action</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
    <ResistanceFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Comforting Wind</Name>
      <Text>You can't suffocate.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <Resistances />
      <Vulnerabilities />
      <Immunities>
        <string>Suffocation</string>
      </Immunities>
      <SavingThrowAdvantages />
    </ResistanceFeature>
    <ResourceFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Wind's Grasp</Name>
      <Text>As a reaction when you fall, you can cause yourself to take no damage from the fall. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Reaction</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <ValueBonus>None</ValueBonus>
      <Value>1</Value>
      <ResourceID>PENNANT_OF_THE_VIND_RUNE_WINDS_GRASP</ResourceID>
      <Recharge>ShortRest</Recharge>
      <ExclusionID />
    </ResourceFeature>
    <BonusSpellFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Wind Walker</Name>
      <Text>While you are attuned to this rune, you can cast levitate as a bonus action. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Bonus</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <Spell>Levitate</Spell>
      <SpellCastingAbility>None</SpellCastingAbility>
      <SpellCastModifier>ShortRest</SpellCastModifier>
      <KeywordsToAdd />
    </BonusSpellFeature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Gift of Wind</Name>
      <Text>You can transfer the pennant's magic to a nonmagical item-a suit of armor, a pair of boots, or a cloak-by tracing the vind rune there with your finger. The transfer takes 8 hours of work that requires the two items to be within 5 feet of each other. At the end, the pennant is destroyed, and the rune appears in silver on the chosen item, which gains a benefit based on its form:
Amor. The armor is now an uncommon magic item that requires attunement. You gain a bonus to speed of 5 feet while you wear the armor, and if it normally imposes disadvantage on Stealth checks, it no longer does so.
Boots/Cloak. The pair of boots or cloak is now a rare magic item that requires attunement. While wearing the item, you can convert up to 20 feet of your movement on each of your turns into flight. If you don't land at the end of this flight, you fall unless you have another means of staying aloft. You can also cast feather fall once from the item, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a short or long rest.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Other</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
  </AttunementFeatures>
  <CarryFeatures />
  <EquipFeatures />
  <AttunedEquipFeatures />
  <OnUseFeatures />
  <AttunedOnUseFeatures />
  <Requirement>Wondrous item</Requirement>
  <Name>Pennant of the Vind Rune</Name>
  <Description>This blue pennant is crafted from silk and is five feet long and whips about as if buffeted by a wind. The vind (wind) rune appears on its surface, looking almost like a cloud. The pennant has the following properties, which work only while it's on your person.</Description>
  <Slot>Wonderous</Slot>
  <Source>Storm King's Thunder</Source>
  <Rarity>VeryRare</Rarity>
</MagicProperty>