<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Background xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Name>Knight of the Order</Name>
  <Description>You belong to an order of knights who have sworn oaths to achieve a certain goal. The nature of this goal depends on the order you serve, but in your eyes it is without question a vital and honorable endeavor. Faerûn has a wide variety of knightly orders, all of which have a similar outlook concerning their actions and responsibilities. Though the term "knight" conjures ideas of mounted, heavily armored warriors of noble blood, most knightly orders in Faerûn don't restrict their membership to such individuals. The goals and philosophies of the order are more important than the gear and fighting style of its members, and so most of these orders aren't limited to fighting types, but are open to all sorts of folk who are willing to battle and die for the order's cause.
The "Knightly Orders of Faerûn" sidebar details several of the orders that are active at present and is designed to help inform your decision about which group you owe allegiance to.</Description>
  <Descriptions>
    <TableDescription>
      <Name>Knightly Orders of Faerûn</Name>
      <Text>Many who rightfully call themselves "knight" earn that title as part of an order in service to a deity, such as Kelemvor's Eternal Order or Mystra's Knights of the Mystic Fire. Other knightly orders serve a government, royal family, or are the elite military of a feudal state, such as the brutal Warlock Knights of Vaasa. Other knighthoods are secular and nongovernmental organizations of warriors who follow a particular philosophy, or consider themselves a kind of extended family, similar to an order of monks. Although there are organizations, such as the Knights of the Shield, that use the trappings of knighthood without necessarily being warriors, most folk of Faerun who hear the word "knight" think of a mounted warrior in armor beholden to a code. Below are a few knightly organizations.
Knights of the Unicorn. The Knights of the Unicorn began as a fad of romantically minded sons and daughters of patriar families in Baldur's Gate. On a lark, they took the unicorn goddess Lurue as their mascot and went on various adventures for fun. The reality of the dangers they faced eventually sank in, as did Lurue's tenets. Over time the small group grew and spread, gaining a following in places as far as Cormyr. The Knights of the Unicorn are chivalric adventurers who follow romantic ideals: life is to be relished and lived with laughter, quests should be taken on a dare, impossible dreams should be pursued for the sheer wonder of their completion, and everyone should be praised for their strengths and comforted in their weaknesses.
Knights of Myth Drannor. Long ago, the Knights of Myth Drannor were a famous adventuring band, and Dove Falcon hand, one of the famous Seven Sisters, was one of them. The band took its name to honor the great but fallen city, just as the new Knights of Myth Drannor do today. With the city once again in ruins, Dove Falconhand decided to reform the group with the primary goal of building alliances and friendship between the civilized races of the world and goodly people in order to combat evil. The Knights of Myth Drannor once again ride the roads of the Dalelands, and they've begun to spread to the lands beyond. Their members, each accepted by Dove herself, are above all valiant and honest.
Knights of the Silver Chalice. The Knights of the Silver Chalice was formed by edict of the demigod Siamorphe in Waterdeep a century ago. Siamorphe's ethos is the nobility's right and responsibility to rule, and the demigod is incarnated as a different noble mortal in each generation. By the decree of the Siamorphe at that time, the Knights of the Silver Chalice took it upon themselves to put a proper heir on the throne of Tethyr and reestablish order in that kingdom. Since then they have grown to be the most popular knighthood in Tethyr, a nation that has hosted many knighthoods in fealty to the crown.
</Text>
      <Amount>1</Amount>
      <UniqueID>KNIGHT_OF_ORDER_ORDER</UniqueID>
      <Entries>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>1</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>1</MaxRoll>
          <Text>Knights of the Unicorn</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>2</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>2</MaxRoll>
          <Text>Knights of Myth Drannor</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>3</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>3</MaxRoll>
          <Text>Knights of the Silver Chalice</Text>
        </TableEntry>
      </Entries>
      <BackgroundOption>None</BackgroundOption>
    </TableDescription>
    <Description>
      <Name>Suggested Characteristics</Name>
      <Text>Use the tables for the soldier background in the Player's Handbook as the basis for your traits and motivations, modifying the entries when appropriate to suit your identity as a knight of your order.
Your bond almost always involves the order to which you belong (or at least key members of it), and it is highly unusual for a knight's ideal not to reflect the agenda, sentiment, or philosophy of one's order.</Text>
    </Description>
  </Descriptions>
  <Features>
    <SkillProficiencyFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Skill Proficiencies</Name>
      <Text>Persuasion</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>true</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <Skills>
        <string>Persuasion</string>
      </Skills>
      <ProficiencyMultiplier>1</ProficiencyMultiplier>
      <BonusType>AddOnlyIfNotProficient</BonusType>
    </SkillProficiencyFeature>
    <SkillProficiencyChoiceFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Skill Proficiencies</Name>
      <Text>Your choice of one from among Arcana, History, Nature, and Religion, as ppropriate for your order</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>true</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <Skills>
        <string>Arcana</string>
        <string>History</string>
        <string>Nature</string>
        <string>Religion</string>
      </Skills>
      <Amount>1</Amount>
      <ProficiencyMultiplier>1</ProficiencyMultiplier>
      <BonusType>AddOnlyIfNotProficient</BonusType>
      <OnlyAlreadyKnownSkills>false</OnlyAlreadyKnownSkills>
      <UniqueID>KNIGHT_OF_THE_ORDER_SKILL</UniqueID>
    </SkillProficiencyChoiceFeature>
    <ToolProficiencyChoiceConditionFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Tool Proficiencies</Name>
      <Text>Your choice of a gaming set or a musical instrument
</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>true</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <Amount>1</Amount>
      <UniqueID>KNIGHT_OF_THE_ORDER_TOOL</UniqueID>
      <Condition>Tool and (Instrument or Game)</Condition>
    </ToolProficiencyChoiceConditionFeature>
    <LanguageChoiceFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Languages</Name>
      <Text>Any one of your choice</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>true</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Amount>1</Amount>
      <UniqueID>KNIGHT_OF_THE_ORDER_LANGUAGE</UniqueID>
    </LanguageChoiceFeature>
    <FreeItemAndGoldFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Equipment</Name>
      <Text>An insignia of rank, a trophy taken from a fallen enemy (a dagger, broken blade, or piece of a banner), a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>true</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Items>
        <string>An insignia of rank</string>
        <string>A trophy taken from a fallen enemy (a dagger, broken blade, or piece of a banner)</string>
        <string>Clothes, Common</string>
        <string>Pouch</string>
      </Items>
      <CP>0</CP>
      <SP>0</SP>
      <GP>10</GP>
    </FreeItemAndGoldFeature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Knightly Regard</Name>
      <Text>Your receive shelter and succor from members of your knightly order and those who are sympathetic to its aims. If your order is a religious one, you can gain aid from temples and other religious communities of your deity. Knights of civic orders can get help from the community — whether a lone settlement or a great nation — that they serve, and knights of philosophical orders can find help from those they have aided in pursuit of their ideals, and those who share their ideals., This help comes in the form of shelter and meals, and healing when appropriate, as well as occasionally risky assistance, such as a band of local citizens rallying to aid a sorely pressed knight, or those who support the order helping to smuggle a knight out of town when he or she is being hunted unjustly.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
  </Features>
  <PersonalityTrait>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>1</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>1</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>I’m always polite and respectful.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>2</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>2</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>I’m haunted by memories of war. I can’t get the images of violence out of my mind.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>3</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>3</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>I’ve lost too many friends, and I’m slow to make new ones.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>4</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>4</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>I’m full of inspiring and cautionary tales from my military experience relevant to almost every combat situation.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>5</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>5</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>I can stare down a hell hound without flinching.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>6</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>6</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>I enjoy being strong and like breaking things.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>7</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>7</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>I have a crude sense of humor.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>8</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>8</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>I face problems head-on. A simple, direct solution is the best path to success.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
  </PersonalityTrait>
  <Ideal>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>1</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>1</MaxRoll>
      <Title>Greater Good</Title>
      <Text>Our lot is to lay down our lives in defense of others. (Good)</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>2</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>2</MaxRoll>
      <Title>Responsibility</Title>
      <Text>I do what I must and obey just authority. (Lawful)</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>3</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>3</MaxRoll>
      <Title>Independence</Title>
      <Text>When people follow orders blindly, they embrace a kind of tyranny. (Chaotic)</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>4</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>4</MaxRoll>
      <Title>Might</Title>
      <Text>In life as in war, the stronger force wins. (Evil)</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>5</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>5</MaxRoll>
      <Title>Live and Let Live</Title>
      <Text>Ideals aren’t worth killing over or going to war for. (Neutral)</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>6</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>6</MaxRoll>
      <Title>Nation</Title>
      <Text>My city, nation, or people are all that matter. (Any)</Text>
    </TableEntry>
  </Ideal>
  <Bond>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>1</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>1</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>I would still lay down my life for the people I served with.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>2</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>2</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>Someone saved my life on the battlefield. To this day, I will never leave a friend behind.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>3</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>3</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>My honor is my life.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>4</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>4</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>I’ll never forget the crushing defeat my company suffered or the enemies who dealt it.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>5</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>5</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>Those who fight beside me are those worth dying for.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>6</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>6</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>I fight for those who cannot fight for themselves.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
  </Bond>
  <Flaw>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>1</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>1</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>The monstrous enemy we faced in battle still leaves me quivering with fear.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>2</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>2</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>I have little respect for anyone who is not a proven warrior.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>3</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>3</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>I made a terrible mistake in battle that cost many lives—and I would do anything to keep that mistake secret.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>4</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>4</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>My hatred of my enemies is blind and unreasoning.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>5</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>5</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>I obey the law, even if the law causes misery.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
    <TableEntry>
      <MinRoll>6</MinRoll>
      <MaxRoll>6</MaxRoll>
      <Title />
      <Text>I’d rather eat my armor than admit when I’m wrong.</Text>
    </TableEntry>
  </Flaw>
  <Source>Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide</Source>
</Background>