<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Monster xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Name>Su-monster</Name>
  <Descriptions />
  <Description>Su-monsters are cunning, wicked primates that inhabit forsaken wilderness areas and caves. Adults stand 5 feet tall and have long prehensile tails. Although they can grasp tools and weapons with their tails or clawed feet, su-monsters prefer to rend prey with their claws. Adult su-monsters can also project blasts of psionic energy that leave enemies stunned and unable to flee or defend themselves.
Asu-monster sleeps while hanging upside down by its tail. While awake, it can also unleash a devastating attack from that position, rending with all four of its claws.
Su-monsters communicate silently by using their prehensile tails to make gestures. They typically kill more than they can eat, burying the leftovers and marking their location with the victim's possessions.</Description>
  <Source>Tomb of Annihilation</Source>
  <Size>Medium</Size>
  <Keywords>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>monstrosity</Name>
    </Keyword>
  </Keywords>
  <Alignment>chaotic evil</Alignment>
  <AC>12</AC>
  <HP>27</HP>
  <HPRoll>5d8 + 5</HPRoll>
  <Speeds>
    <string>30 ft.</string>
    <string>climb 30 ft.</string>
  </Speeds>
  <Strength>14</Strength>
  <Dexterity>15</Dexterity>
  <Constitution>12</Constitution>
  <Intelligence>9</Intelligence>
  <Wisdom>13</Wisdom>
  <Charisma>9</Charisma>
  <Resistances />
  <Vulnerablities />
  <Immunities />
  <ConditionImmunities />
  <Senses />
  <PassivePerception>0</PassivePerception>
  <Languages />
  <CR>1</CR>
  <XP>200</XP>
  <Traits />
  <Actions>
    <MonsterTrait>
      <Name>Multiattack</Name>
      <Text> The su-monster makes two attacks: one with its bite and one with its claws.</Text>
    </MonsterTrait>
    <MonsterAction>
      <Name>Bite</Name>
      <Text> Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4 + 2) piercing damage.</Text>
      <AttackBonus>4</AttackBonus>
      <Damage>1d4 + 2 piercing</Damage>
    </MonsterAction>
    <MonsterAction>
      <Name>Claws</Name>
      <Text> Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (2d4 + 2) slashing damage, or 12 (4d4 + 2) slashing damage if the su-monster is hanging by its tail and all four of its limbs are free.
Psychic Crush (Recharge 5-6). The su-monster targets one creature it can see within 30 feet of it. The target must succeed on a DC 11 Wisdom saving throw or take 17 (5d6) psychic damage and be stunned for 1 minute. The stunned target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</Text>
      <AttackBonus>4</AttackBonus>
      <Damage>2d4 + 2  slashing</Damage>
    </MonsterAction>
  </Actions>
  <Reactions />
  <LegendaryActions />
  <SaveBonus />
  <SkillBonus>
    <MonsterSkillBonus>
      <Skill>Athletics</Skill>
      <Ability>None</Ability>
      <Bonus>4</Bonus>
      <Text />
    </MonsterSkillBonus>
    <MonsterSkillBonus>
      <Skill>Perception</Skill>
      <Ability>None</Ability>
      <Bonus>2</Bonus>
      <Text />
    </MonsterSkillBonus>
  </SkillBonus>
  <Spells />
  <Slots />
</Monster>