<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Monster xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Size>Medium</Size>
  <Name>Imy-Ut Ushabti</Name>
  <Descriptions />
  <Source>Tome of Beasts</Source>
  <Keywords>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>monstrosity</Name>
    </Keyword>
  </Keywords>
  <Alignment>neutral</Alignment>
  <AC>15</AC>
  <ACText>chain shirt</ACText>
  <HP>97</HP>
  <HPRoll>15d8 + 30</HPRoll>
  <Speeds>
    <string>30 ft.</string>
  </Speeds>
  <Strength>17</Strength>
  <Dexterity>14</Dexterity>
  <Constitution>15</Constitution>
  <Intelligence>6</Intelligence>
  <Wisdom>10</Wisdom>
  <Charisma>5</Charisma>
  <Resistances>
    <string>bludgeoning</string>
  </Resistances>
  <Vulnerablities>
    <string>fire</string>
  </Vulnerablities>
  <Immunities />
  <ConditionImmunities>
    <string>exhaustion</string>
    <string>frightened</string>
  </ConditionImmunities>
  <Senses>
    <string>darkvision 60 ft.</string>
  </Senses>
  <PassivePerception>0</PassivePerception>
  <Languages>
    <string>Common (Ancient Nurian)</string>
  </Languages>
  <CR>3</CR>
  <XP>700</XP>
  <Traits>
    <MonsterTrait>
      <Name>Regeneration</Name>
      <Text>The imy-ut ushabti regains 5 hit points at the start of its turn if it has at least 1 hit point.</Text>
    </MonsterTrait>
    <MonsterTrait>
      <Name>Rent wrappings</Name>
      <Text>A creature that touches or deals slashing or piercing damage to an imy-ut ushabti while within 5 feet of the creature shreds its delicate linen wrappings, releasing a flurry of skittering scarabs. The attacking creature must make a DC 12 Dexterity saving throw to avoid them. On a failure, these beetles flow onto the attacker and deal 3 (1d6) piercing damage to it at the start of each of its turns. A creature can remove beetles from itself or from another affected creature within reach by using an action and making a successful DC 12 Dexterity saving throw. The beetles are also destroyed if the affected creature takes damage from an area effect.</Text>
    </MonsterTrait>
  </Traits>
  <Actions>
    <MonsterAction>
      <Name>Ceremonial Greatsword</Name>
      <Text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 10 (2d6 + 3) slashing damage, and the target must make a successful DC 13 Constitution saving throw or take 5 (2d4) poison damage at the start of each of its turns. The target repeats the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</Text>
      <AttackBonus>5</AttackBonus>
      <Damage>2d6 + 3</Damage>
    </MonsterAction>
    <MonsterTrait>
      <Name>Vomit Swarm (1/Day)</Name>
      <Text>The imy-ut ushabti parts its wrappings voluntarily and releases a swarm of scarab beetles that follow its mental commands. The statistics of this swarm are identical to a swarm of insects, but with the following attack instead of a swarm of insects' standard bite attack:</Text>
    </MonsterTrait>
    <MonsterAction>
      <Name>Bites</Name>
      <Text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 0 ft., one creature. Hit: 10 (4d4) piercing damage, or 5 (2d4) piercing damage if the swarm has half of its hit points or fewer, and the target must make a successful DC 13 Constitution saving throw or take 5 (2d4) poison damage at the start of each of its turns. A poisoned creature repeats the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</Text>
      <AttackBonus>3</AttackBonus>
      <Damage>4d4</Damage>
    </MonsterAction>
  </Actions>
  <Reactions />
  <LegendaryActions />
  <SaveBonus>
    <MonsterSaveBonus>
      <Ability>Wisdom</Ability>
      <Bonus>2</Bonus>
    </MonsterSaveBonus>
  </SaveBonus>
  <SkillBonus />
  <Spells />
  <Slots />
</Monster>