<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SubClass xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Features>
    <CollectionChoiceFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Storm of Fury</Name>
      <Text>When you select this path at 3rd level, choose one of the following options: desert, sea, or tundra. The environment you choose shapes the nature of the storm you conjure when you rage.
While raging, you emanate an aura in a 10-foot radius. The effects of this aura depend on your chosen environment.</Text>
      <Level>3</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <Amount>1</Amount>
      <UniqueID>BARBARIAN_STORM_HEREAL_STORM_FURY</UniqueID>
      <Collection>Category = 'Feats/Storm Herald Environments'</Collection>
      <AllowSameChoice>false</AllowSameChoice>
    </CollectionChoiceFeature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Storm Soul</Name>
      <Text>At 6th level, your link to the power of the storm grants you additional abilities based on the environment you chose at 3rd level.</Text>
      <Level>6</Level>
      <Hidden>true</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Shield of the Storm</Name>
      <Text>At 10th level, you learn to use your mastery of the storm to protect your allies. While you are raging, allies within your aura gain the benefits of your Storm Soul feature.</Text>
      <Level>10</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Raging Storm</Name>
      <Text>At 14th level, the power of the storm you channel grows mightier.</Text>
      <Level>14</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
  </Features>
  <MulticlassingFeatures />
  <FirstClassFeatures />
  <MulticlassingSpellLevels />
  <Descriptions />
  <Source>Unearthed Arcana 18 - Barbarian Primal Paths</Source>
  <Name>Path of the Storm Herald</Name>
  <SheetName>Storm Herald</SheetName>
  <Description>Typical barbarians harbor a fury that dwells within. Their rage grants them superior strength, durability, and speed. Barbarians who follow the Path of the Storm Herald learn instead to transform their rage into a mantle of primal magic that swirls around them. When in a fury, a barbarian of this path taps into nature to create powerful, magical effects.
Storm heralds are typically elite champions who train alongside druids, rangers, and others sworn to protect the natural realm. Other storm heralds hone their craft in elite lodges founded in regions wracked by storms, in the frozen reaches at the world’s end, or deep in the hottest deserts.</Description>
  <ParentRace>Barbarian</ParentRace>
</SubClass>