<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SubClass xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Features>
    <ChoiceFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Divine Fury</Name>
      <Text>Starting when you choose this path at 3rd level, you can channel divine fury when you start to rage. If you do so, you become cloaked in an aura of divine power until the rage ends. At the end of each of your turns for that duration, each creature within 5 feet of you takes damage equal to 1d6 + half your barbarian level. The damage is necrotic or radiant; you choose the type of damage when you gain this feature.</Text>
      <Level>3</Level>
      <Hidden>true</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <Choices>
        <Feature>
          <Keywords />
          <Name>Divine Fury - Necrotic</Name>
          <Text>Starting when you choose this path at 3rd level, you can channel divine fury when you start to rage. If you do so, you become cloaked in an aura of divine power until the rage ends. At the end of each of your turns for that duration, each creature within 5 feet of you takes damage equal to 1d6 + half your barbarian level. The damage is necrotic.</Text>
          <Level>3</Level>
          <Hidden>false</Hidden>
          <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
          <Action>Other</Action>
          <Prerequisite />
        </Feature>
        <Feature>
          <Keywords />
          <Name>Divine Fury - Radiant</Name>
          <Text>Starting when you choose this path at 3rd level, you can channel divine fury when you start to rage. If you do so, you become cloaked in an aura of divine power until the rage ends. At the end of each of your turns for that duration, each creature within 5 feet of you takes damage equal to 1d6 + half your barbarian level. The damage is radiant.</Text>
          <Level>3</Level>
          <Hidden>false</Hidden>
          <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
          <Action>Other</Action>
          <Prerequisite />
        </Feature>
      </Choices>
      <Amount>1</Amount>
      <UniqueID>BARBARIAN_ZEALOT_DIVINE_FURY</UniqueID>
      <AllowSameChoice>false</AllowSameChoice>
    </ChoiceFeature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Warrior of the Gods</Name>
      <Text>At 3rd level, your soul is marked for endless battle. If a spell would have the sole effect of restoring you to life (but not undeath), the caster does not need material components to cast the spell on you.</Text>
      <Level>3</Level>
      <Hidden>true</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
    <ResourceFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Zealous Focus</Name>
      <Text>At 6th level, the divine power that fuels your rage can shield you from harm. If you fail a saving throw while raging, you can instead succeed on that saving throw as a reaction. However, doing so immediately ends your rage, and you can’t rage again until you finish a short or long rest.</Text>
      <Level>6</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Reaction</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <ValueBonus>None</ValueBonus>
      <Value>1</Value>
      <ResourceID>BARBARIAN_ZEALOT_FOCUS</ResourceID>
      <Recharge>ShortRest</Recharge>
      <ExclusionID />
    </ResourceFeature>
    <ResourceFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Zealous Presence</Name>
      <Text>At 10th level, you learn to channel divine power to inspire zealotry in others. As an action, you howl in fury and unleash a battle cry infused with divine energy. Every ally within 60 feet of you gains advantage on attack rolls and saving throws until the start of your next turn.
Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.
</Text>
      <Level>10</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Action</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <ValueBonus>None</ValueBonus>
      <Value>1</Value>
      <ResourceID>BARBARIAN_ZEALOT_PRESENCE</ResourceID>
      <Recharge>LongRest</Recharge>
      <ExclusionID />
    </ResourceFeature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Rage Beyond Death</Name>
      <Text>Beginning at 14th level, the divine power that fuels your rage allows you to shrug off fatal blows.
While raging, having 0 hit points doesn’t knock you unconscious. You still must make death saving throws, and you suffer the normal effects of taking damage while at 0 hit points. However, if you would die due to failing death saving throws, you don’t die until your rage ends.</Text>
      <Level>14</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Other</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
  </Features>
  <MulticlassingFeatures />
  <FirstClassFeatures />
  <MulticlassingSpellLevels />
  <Descriptions />
  <Source>Unearthed Arcana 18 - Barbarian Primal Paths</Source>
  <Name>Path of the Zealot</Name>
  <SheetName>Zealot</SheetName>
  <Description>Some deities inspire their followers to pitch themselves into a ferocious battle fury. These barbarians are zealots—warriors who channel their rage into powerful displays of divine power.
A variety of gods across the worlds of D&amp;D inspire their followers to embrace this path. Tempus from the Forgotten Realms and Hextor and Erythnul of Greyhawk are all prime examples. In general, the gods who inspire zealots are deities of combat, destruction, and violence. Not all are evil, but few are good.
Storm heralds are typically elite champions who train alongside druids, rangers, and others sworn to protect the natural realm. Other storm heralds hone their craft in elite lodges founded in regions wracked by storms, in the frozen reaches at the world’s end, or deep in the hottest deserts.</Description>
  <ParentRace>Barbarian</ParentRace>
</SubClass>