<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<MagicProperty xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <AttunementFeatures />
  <CarryFeatures>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Scroll of Protection</Name>
      <Text>Using an action to read the scroll encloses you in an invisible barrier that extends from you to form a 5-foot-radius, 10-foot-high cylinder. For 5 minutes, this barrier prevents celestials from entering or affecting anything within the cylinder. The cylinder moves with you and remains centered on you. However, if you move in such a way that a celestial would be inside the cylinder, the effect ends. A creature can attempt to overcome the barrier by using an action to make a DC 15 Charisma check. On a success, the creature ceases to be affected by the barrier.</Text>
      <Level>0</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>true</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Action</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
  </CarryFeatures>
  <EquipFeatures />
  <AttunedEquipFeatures />
  <OnUseFeatures />
  <AttunedOnUseFeatures />
  <Requirement>Scroll</Requirement>
  <Name>Scroll of Protection (Celestials)</Name>
  <Description>Each scroll ofprotection works against a specific type of creature chosen by the DM or determined randomly by rolling on the following table.
Creature Type
01-10 Aberrations
11-20 Beasts
21-30 Celestials
31-40 Elementals
41-50 Fey
51-75 Fiends
76-80 Plants
81-00 Undead

Using an action to read the scroll encloses you in an invisible barrier that extends from you to form a 5-foot-radius, 10-foot-high cylinder. For 5 minutes, this barrier prevents aberrations from entering or affecting anything within the cylinder. The cylinder moves with you and remains centered on you. However, if you move in such a way that a creature of the specified type would be inside the cylinder, the effect ends. A creature can attempt to overcome the barrier by using an action to make a DC 15 Charisma check. On a success, the creature ceases to be affected by the barrier.</Description>
  <Slot>Wonderous</Slot>
  <Source>Dungeon Master's Guide</Source>
  <Rarity>Rare</Rarity>
</MagicProperty>