<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Monster xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Size>Large</Size>
  <Name>Beholder Zombie</Name>
  <Descriptions />
  <Source>Monster Manual</Source>
  <Keywords>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>undead</Name>
    </Keyword>
  </Keywords>
  <Alignment>neutral evil</Alignment>
  <AC>15</AC>
  <ACText>natural armor</ACText>
  <HP>93</HP>
  <HPRoll>11d10+33</HPRoll>
  <Speeds>
    <string>0 ft.</string>
    <string>fly 20 ft. (hover)</string>
  </Speeds>
  <Strength>10</Strength>
  <Dexterity>8</Dexterity>
  <Constitution>16</Constitution>
  <Intelligence>3</Intelligence>
  <Wisdom>8</Wisdom>
  <Charisma>5</Charisma>
  <Resistances />
  <Vulnerablities />
  <Immunities>
    <string>poison</string>
  </Immunities>
  <ConditionImmunities>
    <string>poisoned</string>
    <string>prone</string>
  </ConditionImmunities>
  <Senses>
    <string>darkvision 60 ft.</string>
  </Senses>
  <PassivePerception>0</PassivePerception>
  <Languages>
    <string>understands Deep Speech and Undercommon but can't speak</string>
  </Languages>
  <CR>5</CR>
  <XP>1800</XP>
  <Traits>
    <MonsterTrait>
      <Name>Undead Fortitude</Name>
      <Text>If damage reduces the zombie to 0 hit points, it must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC of 5+the damage taken, unless the damage is radiant or from a critical hit. On a success, the zombie drops to 1 hit point instead.</Text>
    </MonsterTrait>
  </Traits>
  <Actions>
    <MonsterAction>
      <Name>Bite</Name>
      <Text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 14 (4d6) piercing damage.</Text>
      <AttackBonus>3</AttackBonus>
      <Damage>4d6</Damage>
    </MonsterAction>
    <MonsterTrait>
      <Name>Eye Ray</Name>
      <Text>The zombie uses a random magical eye ray, choosing a target that it can see within 60 feet of it.
1. Paralyzing Ray. The targeted creature must succeed on a DC 14 Constitution saving throw or be paralyzed for 1 minute. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.
2. Fear Ray. The targeted creature must succeed on a DC 14 Wisdom saving throw or be frightened for 1 minute. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.
3. Enervation Ray. The targeted creature must make a DC 14 Constitution saving throw, taking 36 (8d8) necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
4. Disintegration Ray. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 14 Dexterity saving throw or take 45 (10d8) force damage. If this damage reduces the creature to 0 hit points, its body becomes a pile of fine gray dust.
If the target is a Large or smaller nonmagical object or creation of magical force, it is disintegrated without a saving throw. If the target is a Huge or larger nonmagical object or creation of magical force, this ray disintegrates a 10-foot cube of it.</Text>
    </MonsterTrait>
  </Actions>
  <Reactions />
  <LegendaryActions />
  <SaveBonus>
    <MonsterSaveBonus>
      <Ability>Wisdom</Ability>
      <Bonus>3</Bonus>
    </MonsterSaveBonus>
  </SaveBonus>
  <SkillBonus />
  <Spells />
  <Slots />
</Monster>