<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Spell xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Keywords>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>verbal</Name>
    </Keyword>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>somatic</Name>
    </Keyword>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>wizard</Name>
    </Keyword>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>warlock</Name>
    </Keyword>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>sorcerer</Name>
    </Keyword>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>conjuration</Name>
    </Keyword>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>paladin</Name>
    </Keyword>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>ranged</Name>
    </Keyword>
  </Keywords>
  <CantripDamage />
  <Name>Find Vehicle</Name>
  <CastingTime>10 minutes</CastingTime>
  <Range>30 feet</Range>
  <Duration>8 hours</Duration>
  <Level>2</Level>
  <Description>You summon a spirit that assumes the form of a nonmilitary land vehicle of your choice, appearing in an unoccupied space within range. The vehicle has the statistics of a normal vehicle of its sort, though it is celestial, fey, or fiendish your choice in origin. The physical characteristics of the vehicle reflect its origin to some degree. For example, a fiendish SUV might be jet black in color, with tinted windows and a sinister[looking front grille.
You have a supernatural bond with the conjured vehicle that allows you to drive beyond your normal ability. While driving the conjured vehicle, you are considered proficient with vehicles of its type, and you add double your proficiency bonus to ability checks related to driving the vehicle. While driving the vehicle, you can make any spell you cast that targets only you also target the vehicle.
If the vehicle drops to 0 hit points, it disappears, leaving behind no physical form. You can also dismiss the vehicle at any time as an action, causing it to disappear.
You can’t have more than one vehicle bonded by this spell at a time. As an action, you can release the vehicle from its bond at any time, causing it to disappear.</Description>
  <Descriptions>
    <Description>
      <Name>At Higher Levels</Name>
      <Text>When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can conjure a nonmilitary water vehicle large enough to carry six Medium creatures. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you can conjure a nonmilitary air vehicle large enough to carry ten Medium creatures. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, you can conjure any type of vehicle, subject to the DM’s approval.</Text>
    </Description>
  </Descriptions>
  <Source>Unearthed Arcana 7 - Modern Magic</Source>
</Spell>