<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Spell xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Keywords>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>verbal</Name>
    </Keyword>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>somatic</Name>
    </Keyword>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>technomagic</Name>
    </Keyword>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>concentration</Name>
    </Keyword>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>wizard</Name>
    </Keyword>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>warlock</Name>
    </Keyword>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>sorcerer</Name>
    </Keyword>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>enchantment</Name>
    </Keyword>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>ranged</Name>
    </Keyword>
    <Save>
      <Name>save</Name>
      <Throw>Wisdom</Throw>
    </Save>
    <Keyword>
      <Name>sphere</Name>
    </Keyword>
  </Keywords>
  <CantripDamage />
  <Name>Haywire</Name>
  <CastingTime>1 action</CastingTime>
  <Range>90 feet</Range>
  <Duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</Duration>
  <Level>3</Level>
  <Description>This spell plays havoc with electronic devices, making the use of such devices all but impossible. Each electronic device in a 10-foot-radius sphere centered on a point you choose within range is subject to random behavior while it remains within the area. A device not held by a creature is automatically affected. If an electronic device is held by a creature, that creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or have the device affected by the spell.</Description>
  <Descriptions>
    <TableDescription>
      <Name>Haywire</Name>
      <Text>At the start of each of your turns, roll a d6 for each affected device to determine its behavior. Except where otherwise indicated, that behavior lasts until the start of your next turn while this spell is in effect.</Text>
      <Amount>0</Amount>
      <Entries>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>1</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>1</MaxRoll>
          <Text>The device shuts down and must be restarted. Do not roll again for this device until it is restarted.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>2</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>4</MaxRoll>
          <Text>The device does not function</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>5</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>5</MaxRoll>
          <Text>The device experiences a power surge, causing an electric shock to the wielder if any and one random creature within 5 feet of the device. Each affected creature must make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC, taking 6d6 lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>6</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>6</MaxRoll>
          <Text> The device is usable as normal.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
      </Entries>
      <BackgroundOption>None</BackgroundOption>
    </TableDescription>
    <Description>
      <Name>At Higher Levels</Name>
      <Text>When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the radius of the sphere affected by the spell increases by 5 feet for each slot level above 3rd.</Text>
    </Description>
  </Descriptions>
  <Source>Unearthed Arcana 7 - Modern Magic</Source>
</Spell>