<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SubClass xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Features>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Wild Magic Surge</Name>
      <Text>Starting when you choose this origin at 1st level, your spellcasting can unleash surges of untamed magic. Immediately after you cast a sorcerer spell of 1st level or higher, the DM can have you roll a d20. If you roll a 1, roll on the Wild Magic Surge table to create a random magical effect.
If a Wild Magic effect is a spell, it’s too wild to be affected by Metamagic. If it normally requires concentration, it doesn’t require concentration in this case; the spell lasts for its full duration.</Text>
      <Level>1</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Other</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
    <ResourceFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Tides of Chaos</Name>
      <Text>Starting at 1st level, you can manipulate the forces of chance and chaos to gain advantage on one attack roll, ability check, or saving throw. Once you do so, you must finish a long rest before you can use this feature again. 
Any time before you regain the use of this feature, the DM can have you roll on the Wild Magic Surge table immediately after you cast a sorcerer spell of 1st level or higher. You then regain the use of this feature.</Text>
      <Level>1</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Other</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <ValueBonus>None</ValueBonus>
      <Value>1</Value>
      <ResourceID>WILD_MAGIC_TIDES_OF_CHAOS</ResourceID>
      <Recharge>LongRest</Recharge>
      <ExclusionID />
    </ResourceFeature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Bend Luck</Name>
      <Text>Starting at 6th level, you have the ability to twist fate using your wild magic. When another creature you can see makes an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw, you can use your reaction and spend 2 sorcery points to roll 1d4 and apply the number rolled as a bonus or penalty (your choice) to the creature’s roll. You can do so after the creature rolls but before any effects of the roll occur.</Text>
      <Level>6</Level>
      <Hidden>true</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Reaction</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Controlled Chaos</Name>
      <Text>At 14th level, you gain a modicum of control over the surges of your wild magic. Whenever you roll on the Wild Magic Surge table, you can roll twice and use either number.</Text>
      <Level>14</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Spell Bombardment</Name>
      <Text>Beginning at 18th level, the harmful energy of your spells intensifies. When you roll damage for a spell and roll the highest number possible on any of the dice, choose one of those dice, roll it again and add that roll to the damage. You can use the feature only once per turn. </Text>
      <Level>18</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Other</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
  </Features>
  <MulticlassingFeatures />
  <FirstClassFeatures />
  <MulticlassingSpellLevels />
  <Descriptions>
    <TableDescription>
      <Name>Wild Magic Surge</Name>
      <Amount>0</Amount>
      <Entries>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>1</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>2</MaxRoll>
          <Text>Roll on this table at the start of each of your turns for the next minute, ignoring this result on subsequent rolls.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>3</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>4</MaxRoll>
          <Text>For the next minute, you can see any invisible creature if you have line of sight to it.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>5</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>6</MaxRoll>
          <Text>A modron chosen and controlled by the DM appears in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you, then disappears 1 minute later.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>7</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>8</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You cast fireball as a 3rd-level spell centered on yourself.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>9</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>10</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You cast magic missile as a 5th-level spell.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>11</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>12</MaxRoll>
          <Text>Roll a d10. Your height changes by a number of inches equal to the roll. If the roll is odd, you shrink. If the roll is even, you grow.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>13</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>14</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You cast confusion centered on yourself.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>15</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>16</MaxRoll>
          <Text>For the next minute, you regain 5 hit points at the start of each of your turns.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>17</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>18</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You grow a long beard made of feathers that remains until you sneeze, at which point the feathers explode out from your face.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>19</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>20</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You cast grease centered on yourself.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>21</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>22</MaxRoll>
          <Text>Creatures have disadvantage on saving throws against the next spell you cast in the next minute that involves a saving throw.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>23</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>24</MaxRoll>
          <Text>Your skin turns a vibrant shade of blue. A remove curse spell can end this effect.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>25</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>26</MaxRoll>
          <Text>An eye appears on your forehead for the next minute. During that time, you have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>27</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>28</MaxRoll>
          <Text>For the next minute, all your spells with a casting time of 1 action have a casting time of 1 bonus action.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>29</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>30</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You teleport up to 60 feet to an unoccupied space of your choice that you can see.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>31</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>32</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You are transported to the Astral Plane until the end ofyour next turn, after which time you return to the space you previously occupied or the nearest unoccupied space ifthat space is occupied.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>33</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>34</MaxRoll>
          <Text>Maximize the damage of the next damaging spell you cast within the next minute.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>35</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>36</MaxRoll>
          <Text>Roll a d10. Your age changes by a number of years equal to the roll. If the roll is odd, you get younger (minimum 1 year old). If the roll is even, you get older.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>37</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>38</MaxRoll>
          <Text>1d6 flumphs controlled by the DM appear in unoccupied spaces within 60 feet of you and are frightened of you. They vanish after 1 minute.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>39</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>40</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You regain 2d10 hit points.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>41</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>42</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You turn into a potted plant until the start of your next turn. While a plant, you are incapacitated and have vulnerability to all damage. If you drop to 0 hit points, your pot breaks, and your form reverts.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>43</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>44</MaxRoll>
          <Text>For the next minute, you can teleport up to 20 feet as a bonus action on each of your turns.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>45</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>46</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You cast levitate on yourself.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>47</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>48</MaxRoll>
          <Text>A unicorn controlled by the DM appears in a space within 5 feet of you, then disappears 1 minute later.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>49</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>50</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You can't speak fo rthe next minute. Whenever you try, pink bubbles float out of your mouth.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>51</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>52</MaxRoll>
          <Text>A spectral shield hovers near you for the next minute, granting you a +2 bonus to AC and immunity to magic missile.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>53</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>54</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You are immune to being intoxicated by alcohol for the next 5d6 days.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>55</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>56</MaxRoll>
          <Text>Your hair falls out but grows back within 24 hours.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>57</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>58</MaxRoll>
          <Text>For the next minute, any flammable object you touch that isn't being worn or carried by another creature bursts into flame.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>59</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>60</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You regain your lowest-level expended spell slot.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>61</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>62</MaxRoll>
          <Text>For the next minute, you must shout when you speak.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>63</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>64</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You cast fog cloud centered on yourself.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>65</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>66</MaxRoll>
          <Text>Up to three creatures you choose within 30 feet of you take 4d10 lightning damage.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>67</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>68</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You are frightened by the nearest creature until the end of your next turn.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>69</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>70</MaxRoll>
          <Text>Each creature within 30 feet of you becomes invisible for the next minute. The invisibility ends on a creature when it attacks or casts a spell.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>71</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>72</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You gain resistance to all damage for the next minute.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>73</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>74</MaxRoll>
          <Text>A random creature within 60 feet of you becomes poisoned for 1d4 hours.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>75</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>76</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You glow with bright light in a 30-foot radius for the next minute. Any creature that ends its turn within 5 feet of you is blinded until the end of its next turn.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>77</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>78</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You cast polymorph on yourself. If you fail the saving throw, you turn into a sheep for the spell's duration.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>79</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>80</MaxRoll>
          <Text>Illusory butterflies and flower petals flutter in the air within 10 feet of you for the next minute.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>81</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>82</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You can take one additional action immediately.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>83</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>84</MaxRoll>
          <Text>Each creature within 30 feet of you takes 1d10 necrotic damage. You regain hit points equal to the sum of the necrotic damage dealt.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>85</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>86</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You cast mirror image.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>87</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>88</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You cast fly on a random creature within 60 feet of you.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>89</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>90</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You become invisible for the next minute. During that time, other creatures can't hear you. The invisibility ends if you attack or cast a spell.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>91</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>92</MaxRoll>
          <Text>If you die within the next minute, you immediately come back to life as if by the reincarnate spell.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>93</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>94</MaxRoll>
          <Text>Your size increases by one size category for the next minute.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>95</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>96</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You and all creatures within 30 feet of you gain vulnerability to piercing damage for the next minute.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>97</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>98</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You are surrounded by faint, ethereal music for the next minute.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
        <TableEntry>
          <MinRoll>99</MinRoll>
          <MaxRoll>100</MaxRoll>
          <Text>You regain all expended sorcery points.</Text>
        </TableEntry>
      </Entries>
      <BackgroundOption>None</BackgroundOption>
    </TableDescription>
  </Descriptions>
  <Source>Player's Handbook</Source>
  <Name>Wild Magic</Name>
  <SheetName>Wild Sorcerer</SheetName>
  <Description>Your innate magic comes from draconic magic that was mingled with your blood or that of your ancestors. Most often, sorcerers with this origin trace their descent back to a mighty sorcerer of ancient times who made a bargain with a dragon or who might even have claimed a dragon parent. Some of these bloodlines are well established in the world, but most are obscure. Any given sorcerer could be the first of a new bloodline, as a result of a pact or some other exceptional circumstance.</Description>
  <ParentRace>Sorcerer</ParentRace>
</SubClass>