<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SubClass xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Features>
    <ResourceFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Steady Aim</Name>
      <Text>Beginning when you choose this archetype at 3rd level, your aim becomes deadly. As a bonus action on your turn, you can take careful aim at a creature you can see that is within range of a ranged weapon you’re wielding. Until the end of this turn, your ranged attacks with that weapon gain two benefits against the target:
• The attacks ignore half and three-quarters cover.
• On each hit, the weapon deals additional damage to the target equal to 2 + half your fighter level. 
You can use this feature three times. You regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</Text>
      <Level>3</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Bonus</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <ValueBonus>None</ValueBonus>
      <Value>3</Value>
      <ResourceID>FIGHTER_SHARPSHOOTER_STEADY_AIM</ResourceID>
      <Recharge>ShortRest</Recharge>
      <ExclusionID />
    </ResourceFeature>
    <SkillProficiencyChoiceFeature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Careful Eyes</Name>
      <Text>Starting at 7th level, you excel at picking out hidden enemies and other threats. You can take the Search action as a bonus action.
You also gain proficiency in the Perception, Investigation, or Survival skill (choose one).</Text>
      <Level>7</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
      <Skills>
        <string>Perception</string>
        <string>Investigation</string>
        <string>Survival</string>
      </Skills>
      <Amount>1</Amount>
      <ProficiencyMultiplier>1</ProficiencyMultiplier>
      <BonusType>AddOnlyIfNotProficient</BonusType>
      <OnlyAlreadyKnownSkills>false</OnlyAlreadyKnownSkills>
      <UniqueID>FIGHTER_SHARPSHOOTER_CAREFUL_EYES</UniqueID>
    </SkillProficiencyChoiceFeature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Close-Quarters Shooting</Name>
      <Text>At 10th level, you learn to handle yourself in close combat. Making a ranged attack roll while within 5 feet of an enemy doesn’t impose disadvantage on your roll. In addition, if you hit a creature within 5 feet of you with a ranged attack on your turn, that creature can’t take reactions until the end of this turn.</Text>
      <Level>10</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Hidden</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Rapid Strike</Name>
      <Text>Starting at 15th level, you learn to trade accuracy for swift strikes. If you have advantage on a weapon attack against a target on your turn, you can forgo that advantage to immediately make an additional weapon attack against the same target as a bonus action.</Text>
      <Level>15</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Bonus</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
    <Feature>
      <Keywords />
      <Name>Snap Shot</Name>
      <Text>Starting at 18th level, you are ever ready to spring into action. If you take the Attack action on your first turn of a combat, you can make one additional ranged weapon attack as part of that action.</Text>
      <Level>18</Level>
      <Hidden>false</Hidden>
      <NoDisplay>false</NoDisplay>
      <Action>Other</Action>
      <Prerequisite />
    </Feature>
  </Features>
  <MulticlassingFeatures />
  <FirstClassFeatures />
  <MulticlassingSpellLevels />
  <Descriptions />
  <Source>Unearthed Arcana 22 - Fighter</Source>
  <Name>Sharpshooter</Name>
  <SheetName>Sharpshooter</SheetName>
  <Description>The Sharpshooter is a master of ranged combat. An excellent sniper and eagle-eyed scout, this fighter is a perilous foe who can defeat an entire war band so long as they are kept at range. </Description>
  <ParentRace>Fighter</ParentRace>
</SubClass>